this video is sponsored by audible
thanks guys
do you want to see something you don't
see every day
i was flying along i hopped in i'm just
aqua town and look at what
i found what the heck
now i don't know if this is intentional
or not but i'm thinking there's a
wandering trainer
that somehow has spawned
oh yeah there he is
what are you doing the chances of this
are astronomical
they've spawned and the llama is dang i
thought it was a superhero
look look how majestic oh look at this
this is a new superhero i'm here to save
equitone yay
i'm not the villager that they wanted
but i'm the one that they need
anyway you've distracted me for long
enough i hope that they just stay there
because this is hilarious
so anyway the reason that i've come here
is because it is time
to work and finish the hc bbs now the
entrance
is over here and impulse has been very
busy
making the beginning so if i take my
music disc
i hop in the minecart this should
in theory work if i just play the music
disc it should launch me
there we go brilliant
that is so slick the redstone on that is
brilliant
so now that we're here it is time
to start working on the hc bbs
as you can see we've got the track and
it needs to be
properly finished now i've been
considering how to go about this
and what themes to add and there were a
bunch of really great
suggestions so i mean this is not a
small task this is going to take
an awful lot of time now as we know we
got impulse involved
last episode and he has decorated his
own section of the track which i don't
really want to ruin but it looks like
he's gone for just pure color instead of
any kind of like you know
theming and then yeah he's got he's even
included some shulker boxes which i
didn't expect
him to do that's amazing so maybe we'll
check that out when we've got our
sections done
but i want to add some secret rooms i
want to add different
ways you could go so basically when
you're traveling along
on the minecart you can press buttons to
change your direction
and it gives a lot more variety to this
shopping experience
so i don't know if we'll be able to get
the whole thing done in one session i
don't have
three you know three whole days to go
and do this so let's do a couple of
sections
and let's begin
[Music]
i'm not gonna lie i may have bitten off
a bit more than i can chew for this one
so as you can see i have made quite a
lot
of our hc bbs and there has even been a
bit more redstone work done
by the fabulous impulse now we've not
done any kind of test run yet but i have
added a couple of secrets so you can see
every time the track changes that means
that there's an
alternate route that you can take so i
don't want to spoil where all of the
track changes are but maybe i'll show
you the most obvious one
this one here so if you basically if you
right click this it changes the track
long enough
for you to go down this route here now i
haven't got any easter eggs to put in
here
but if you saw in the time lapse i
actually made a couple of rooms
which are a little bit unique so if you
can find the way to change the track
here at this point
you go down this route now it looks like
it's just part of the
abandoned supermarket but no there's a
little bit of an easter egg
because here is a copy of the original
barge so it's a bit of a throwback and
i've even created like a
fake shopping district mushroom island
from the beginning
i don't know why i put the hep building
there because chronologically
so incorrect the hep building didn't
come in until
way after all of this was gone so i
don't know why i chose that but i don't
know it's kind of iconic
so we got our original barge and you may
have noticed that there are currently no
shulker boxes here
there's no point doing the shulker boxes
until way at the end
but it connects up to impulses section
here and then you go on a ride and then
it comes out of impulses section here
and you can see i've been very very busy
and this is a bit that didn't actually
make it in the timelapse but check it
out
danger danger go back and then i've
added a few little jokes in here
guess you can't go back and then you
come through this
very dangerous looking segment here and
that is as far as i've got for now
because
blimey i need a break i need five
minutes to breathe five minutes to chat
because it's
been a very very long project but the
thing that i really want to do
is give it a test after building this i
haven't tested
any of it so i reckon we should give it
a little whirl
now before we test it a quick word from
today's sponsors i really
appreciate the fact that you guys sit
through this and there's a cameo from my
cat so
quick word from our sponsors it's no
secret that i'm a big fan of audible
it's an app that lets you listen to
any audio title wherever you want in the
past i've talked about how i've listened
to the same
seven audio books on repeat non-stop
but over the last 12 months it's been
pretty difficult
and i've spent more time at home than
ever before
and it's fair to say i've gone a little
bit peculiar
professor so i decided to branch out and
listen to a wider variety of things
turns out audible has more than seven
audiobooks to offer to stop me going
crazy i
listened to some guided meditation some
more sci-fi stories
and even boot camp for the brain it's
fair to say that for me
having that extra voice in the room has
done
wonders for my mental well-being over
the last year
and at the moment audible members get
access to the plus catalogue which is
basically an all you can listen service
that doesn't use up any of your audio
book tokens which is great for someone
like me
who wants to listen to a wider variety
of things and try
some other audio titles out my book
recommendation this time is the martian
by andy weir it had me grip from the
second i started listening to it
and if you're a fan of space and science
i thoroughly recommend it it does have a
little bit of bad language
but if you like those things then this
is definitely worth a listen
if you feel like you could use that
extra voice in the room at the moment
then head on over to audible.com forward
slash korean or
text green to 500 500 there is a link in
the description
and you can start a 30-day free trial of
audible
thank you for watching this little ad
segment and if you are interested the
link is in the description again that's
audible.comgreen
now let's get back into the episode i've
just figured out
that you can jump backwards like look at
if you walk backwards and jump
what i i can't quite work out
what what's happening here weird so as
promised
here is our first test of the hc bbs
since building it
so you've seen this intro bit before so
i'll
just skip to the end of the tunnel all
right here we go
so this is what it feels like there'll
be loads of shulker boxes around to open
oh goodness this goes really fast
oh man okay here's impulses section why
what
[Music]
this is amazing i can get some stuff
oh no no i hit i hit shift i've lost it
i've lost i've lost it
it's gone okay let's try that again i'm
just going to skip to where i messed up
so in this game the problem is
when you are shift-clicking through a
inventory you basically will always
leave the mine cart so
anyone that wants to play this game will
have to go into their options
and they'll need to change their
controls
so i'll do that now so it says there i
need to press
a very strange button in order to
dismount meaning that i'll be able to
shift click that is a problem that we
knew about
i just forgot about it so let's try this
again and i'm going to skip to where i
messed up
blimey this thing goes so fast
i don't know if anyone's going to be
able to get anything out of this
this is where we got to before oh
impulse is a magician
look at this what on earth
what's he done there was that
intentional
oh wow look at that magic i feel oh and
there's shulker boxes there
this goes so quickly oh
oh no we almost made it i've just needed
a bit of track
tell you what let's just continue
because there's only a little bit left
[Music]
because you can't go back and then you
go through here
so there's still as you can hear the
song is still going on
[Music]
okay so that is another
minute that i need to create i need to
create another minutes
worth of track which is
uh that's a lot of work if we're talking
six hours for this bit and this is only
10 seconds i i'm in trouble i don't know
if there's any other hermits that would
be interested in making a small segment
of track
but if they are please please get in
touch
i could use some help right we're
getting pretty hc bbs heavy on this
episode so what i want to do is just
take a quick break we are going to
continue it because that's
basically the big project that i need to
get done
but i i just i need a breather it's too
much at once oh wow look at the majestic
shopping district
okay so i saw that there's something
going on in i don't even want to call
this aqua town it makes aqua town makes
this place
seem far too safe and happy look at
this this town is essentially the
monster mash
there's just mobs everywhere and it's
raining
i'll admit i don't know what's going on
with all the pigs
this this is new to me i don't know why
some of these
pens are pigs and some of them
are not but i did read
that there is basically a competition
here and
each plot is up for sale in aqua town
and there's bids on each one now i would
actually
like some extra land i actually got this
way before aquatan even existed but over
here
i'm thinking this place is so dangerous
over here i'm thinking this
might be a good place you know what i
could just put a bid on
most of them and just see what happens
i'll just put five diamonds on each
of these plots and we'll see if we win
any and i can just keep an eye on it
it ends on the 24th which is not long
away
how funny would it be if i just won all
of it and last
one done bid on each one
uh nope there's more do you know what i
really hope that i don't win
all of them i don't i don't have enough
time to fill each of these plots i just
i want to win one
so i'm just spreading out my bets over
multiple plots
i only really want one plot so i don't
know what i'll do with the land if i
win more than one maybe i haven't
thought this through
ah it's worked for me in the past oh my
goodness
oh my god i think i figured it out so
i've just put a bid on each one of these
now i can only
assume that these belong to b-dubs
and there's a clear book with
instructions check it out
scar has put this up good times realty
ladge
with views contact scar for more info
scar
instead of making a book easy to read
catches the eye he's got a pigsty with
some signs on it that are so difficult
to read best land in town contact scar
for more info
this is nuts because i don't think
anyone is gonna like i didn't see these
i thought that these
they look lovely i couldn't even read
the signs i didn't even realize
that there were signs i think point to
b-dubs on this one cause
i was immediately attracted to the
lectern i just thought these were really
fancy
street lights and balloons so it looks
like you have to negotiate with scar
individually what's a large lot hang on
how long have these been getting away
with this you guys see this right
huh they just vanished
weird oh there's another one wait where
did it go
something weird is happening here i
don't know if you guys know this but i
have
everyone's doors labeled and i've got
them stored in multiple
shulk shulker boxes so i need to do a
bit of maintenance in the barge
i've created this whole extra new space
but i haven't actually done anything
with it so i actually need to move some
of the logs over
while i move all of this stuff over why
don't have a quick
chat about my new series basically i
started a new series called third life
it's a minecraft hardcore
experience but with a little bit of a
twist
and it's definitely worth giving a shot
if you didn't already it looks like most
of you already clicked
you have no idea how scared i was about
uploading something different because
i've been doing hermitcraft now for over
three years and it's kind of taken over
my channel
and i just wanted to try something
different with a different vibe
that took the pressure off because
hermitcraft videos
i love them i love making hermitcraft
videos they are amazing
but they do take up an awful lot of time
as in it takes me about three to four
days to make one
and if i'm busy at any point that
hermitcraft video gets delayed and
delayed and delayed and it
it really does pile on the stress
essentially so
having a different series that's a bit
easier to
upload is a huge
huge stress reliever for me so the fact
that
people have not only clicked on the
video but they seem to have enjoyed it
i just have to say massive thank you it
means it means everything to me
so if you haven't checked it out do give
it a go and also
i i can't believe this nick you know me
i don't ever
really ask for subscriptions on youtube
but uploading that video
i did actually at the end of the video
say hey do you want to subscribe and
i couldn't believe it i couldn't believe
it it was like
10 000 people in one day it was it was
absolutely insane so i can't there must
be a lot of people that are watching
this
episode that aren't subscribed if you're
not please do consider it because it
does
actually help the channel quite a lot
anyway that was a there's a bit of a
real talk there for a second
but uh basically it's all good things
hermitcraft videos will not be
interrupted by the new series
simply because the new series doesn't
take long to record at all we record it
all in one session and one evening
basically means i'm less stressed out
during the week and i can work on
other things like hermitcraft so it's
basically a win-win more videos overall
but anyway enough of that we've got some
movements to do we go we've got a brand
new
log stand i've been meaning to do that
for a while now so i'm glad that that's
out the way
got everything i think that looks pretty
nice i still need to do a lot of
decorating in here anyway
i mean there's there's a lot to do in
general but i'm glad that that's out the
way just need to put the price on
there we go okay i think i've had a long
enough break from
the hcbs and i'm quite ready
to get back into it because this project
unless i just sort of
grip my teeth and get it done it's it's
basically not
gonna get done so let's get into another
time lapse of building this thing and
try and get a bit more done
there is a whole no well another minutes
worth of
track to try and get maybe i can kind of
cheat a little bit
in the sense that i can slow down the
the player
a little bit with some with some
trickery but other than that there's not
a lot i can do but i the good news is i
still have a lot of space to work with
up here so let's see
what we can get done in the rest of this
episode let's go
i hope you like throwbacks because we
are done with the second half
of the hc bbs in fact i've done
all the segments that i want to make so
we've already been through these and all
the secrets
i will admit there's still a little bit
of work to do but
i have added as you saw in the time
lapse a throwback
to season six the old
base and i tell you it's uh it's
actually really difficult to build this
on a small scale but you
you know what it is you recognize that
right of course only if you've watched
season six
in fact some of these may not make any
sense at all this is impulses bit we've
been through this
and then we go to the hall of jokes
and over the lovely calming
souls of madness right so there's two
options here
you can either turn left up the secret
passage there or you turn
right and admittedly they go through the
same
sort of thing it's a pitch black room
it's meant to be really difficult to see
where the shulker boxes are
as you go through right now we're on to
the new segment
where we get to man i think this is the
only time we're gonna see him again
it is the poultry cave or a miniature
version of the poultry cave
and i didn't really know what to do for
these two rooms here but then i just got
kind of like a hit of nostalgia and i
wanted to make something
for everyone that's been around for a
long time and would recognize
what these are and the second room
is a throwback also to season six and
this is
ren bob's rv so
the track actually goes through there
and this is what i mean i've still got a
little bit of decorating to do but the
actual track
is now complete even if there's i need
to add a few more secrets and such
but other than that this will take you
all the way
to the end so i think
for the last time we should
get ourselves another test run
of the hc bbs in full and hope that the
track
is all complete so i'm ready if you're
ready
this is gonna be the final test pretty
much
for this episode at least because i've
still got a little bit of work to do but
let's do it here we go welcome to the hc
bbs the hermitcraft big badge sweep
your task is simple open shulker boxes
and grab items
here's the shulker box coming up now see
if you can open it
oh dear it's empty the ones coming up
though
won't be your task is to grab as many
items as possible but here's the catch
you have extremely limited time don't
dawdle and make sure you look around
looks like you're about to begin good
luck
[Music]
oh the timing of this is amazing
through the poultry cave
through the rv
i think the song might be a little bit
too long
[Music]
okay i don't know how long it goes on
for
i'm gonna see the song through to the
[Music]
end
okay so we got quite a lot
of extra time to fill so i can make the
actual song a bit shorter
or what's more likely is that i need to
slow down
the player through all the tracks now
i'm probably going to use
impulse for this and also the track will
depend
on how long and i also realize that it's
so confusing because i say track
as in the rail the railway track
not the track of the record
it even confuses me sometimes so i can
either make the song a bit shorter
but then all of these little shortcuts
or well they're not even shortcuts all
of these detours
that send you on access journeys to
other
rarer shulker boxes they will also
increase the amount of time that you're
on the rail track
so i'm gonna need impulse's help to make
this all timed
perfectly but we did make it all the way
to the end with
no issues pretty much so from that point
we have succeeded in making the hcbbs
and i think it's actually come out
really well there's
enough diversity in all of the builds
there's some really nice
jokes and of course it's been quite a
nice collaborative effort between
me and impulse so how do you feel about
this project it has been oh man
i've got to admit over like 30 to 40
hours that's that's why this episode has
taken me so long i've basically just
spent my entire time making this and i
can't tell you how excited i am
to actually see some people play this
shopping experience and see if i can
make some more
diamonds but unfortunately that is the
end of today's episode i know
i've basically just spent all of it
making this but i've enjoyed this
project
and i just i just need to see it
finished so
that's it for now thank you very much
for watching i hope you have enjoyed
this episode
and i shall see you in the next one
where hopefully it will be entirely
finished
and we can start doing a grand opening
okay
thank you very much for watching and
good bye
you